<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-07-19T22:29:43+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">POLA Software Testing</title><entry><title type="html">another post</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/06/29/another-post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="another post" /><published>2018-06-29T11:12:32+01:00</published><updated>2018-06-29T11:12:32+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/06/29/another-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/06/29/another-post.html">&lt;p&gt;first paragraph blah blah blah blah blah blah&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;second paragraph&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">first paragraph blah blah blah blah blah blah</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mind mapping: an agile software tester’s friend</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/06/29/mindmap-planning.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mind mapping: an agile software tester's friend" /><published>2017-06-29T11:56:45+01:00</published><updated>2017-06-29T11:56:45+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/06/29/mindmap-planning</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/06/29/mindmap-planning.html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve been told that mind mapping is my best contribution to my current team. While I like to think I’ve made a number of great contributions, the teams really love this one. The understanding of scope and general problem domain, as well as the discussions that this brings, are really fantastic. And you end up with your test cases enumerated! I feel far more confident to say we’re done when I can look at this and understand the test coverage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t given mind mapping a go, try this out:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;grab a pen and paper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;sit down with someone(s) knowledgable in the problem, preferably from the user and technical perspectives&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;write the name of the feature in the middle of the page&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;what are the main ways that you would slice up the story? e.g. what are the primary features? Use these as the initial branches.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;let your thoughts spider out… avoid the temptation to write lists!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;once the mind map seems complete I also find it useful to then note the level of testing we’d like to target against the various elements of the map e.g. unit, API, UI&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;get satisfaction as you implement tests and cross them off the map ;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t think I’ve had a mind mapping session that I’ve felt was a waste of time. It’s amazing how there are almost always interesting and useful discussions to be had about the problem, and so many more test cases to come out of this when two (or more) people chat about it together. Or if it’s done “properly” - before coding begins - issues highlighted that might need addressing before the story is even started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of us are in this business because we’re problem solvers, and it’s often surprisingly enjoyable to talk the problem through and see it become a useful visual representation.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I’ve been told that mind mapping is my best contribution to my current team. While I like to think I’ve made a number of great contributions, the teams really love this one. The understanding of scope and general problem domain, as well as the discussions that this brings, are really fantastic. And you end up with your test cases enumerated! I feel far more confident to say we’re done when I can look at this and understand the test coverage.</summary></entry></feed>